<?xml version='1.0'?>

<project>
        <name>FALKOLib</name>

        <author>
		<name>Fabjan Kallasi</name>
		<url>http://rimlab.ce.unipr.it/Kallasi.html</url>
	</author>
        <author>
		<name>Dario Lodi Rizzini</name>
		<url>http://rimlab.ce.unipr.it/LodiRizzini.html</url>
	</author>
        <author>
		<name>Stefano Caselli</name>
		<url>http://rimlab.ce.unipr.it/Caselli.html</url>
	</author>

        <url>http://rimlab.ce.unipr.it/</url>

        <briefdescription>
         FALKOLib is a library containing keypoint detectors for the stable detection 
         of interest points in laser measurements and two descriptors for robust associations.
	</briefdescription>

        <description>
         Detecting features in sensor measurements and distinguishing among 
         them is an important capability for robot localization and navigation. 
         Despite the wide diffusion of range finders, there are few works 
         on keypoint features for 2D LIDAR and there is potential for improvement 
         over the existing methods. 
         We propose two novel keypoint detectors for the stable detection of 
         interest points in laser measurements (named FALKO and OC) 
         and two descriptors for robust associations (named BSC and CGH). 
         The features defined by combining keypoints and descriptors allow 
         stable and efficient place recognition. 
	</description>

        <requirement>
         Developed and tested under Linux (tested with GCC >= 4.8). 
         Library dependencies: Eigen 3.0, Boost.
         CMake is needed for building. 
	</requirement>
	<map>feature maps</map>

	<input>The approach takes raw laser range data. 
         Laser scans with higher resolution (0.25 deg) enables richer description of the environment.
         Odometry can be used for testing the association between features 
        </input>

	<logformat> 
	 Carmen log format. Raw scan data. 
	</logformat>

	<image> 
		<url>http://rimlab.ce.unipr.it/img/falko-bsc.png</url>
		<description>Example of feature association with FALKO detector and BSC descriptors.</description>
		<url>http://rimlab.ce.unipr.it/img/intel-lab-falko-map.png</url>
		<description>Example of FALKO keypoint (red points) extraction in intel-lab dataset</description>
	</image>

	<paper>
		<title>Fast Keypoint Features from Laser Scanner for Robot Localization and Mapping</title>
		<authorlist>F. Kallasi, D. Lodi Rizzini, and S. Caselli.</authorlist>
		<publishedin>IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L), 1(1):176-183</publishedin>
		<year>2016</year>
		<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/LRA.2016.2517210</url>
	</paper>

<!--	<paper>-->
<!--		<title>Efficient Loop Closure based on FALKO LIDAR Features for Online Robot Localization and Mapping</title>-->
<!--		<authorlist>F. Kallasi and D. Lodi Rizzini.</authorlist>-->
<!--		<publishedin>Subimitted to IEEE/RSJ Int. Conf. on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)</publishedin>-->
<!--		<year>2016</year>-->
<!--	</paper>-->

	<license>FALKOLib is licenced under the Creative Commons
	(Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike).</license>

	<furthermore>
         FALKOLib is designed as a stand-alone library that can be included in your projects. 
         For any questions, comments or installation problems please contact either kallasi@ce.unipr.it or dlr@ce.unipr.it.
	</furthermore>
	 
</project>
